Guide to the Marcel Kurpershoek Papers AD.MC.054
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
P. Marcel Kurpershoek papers
1970-2020
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
Kurpershoek, Marcel
AD.MC.054
15.5 Linear Feet in 30 boxes, 7 cassette cases, circa 120 books, and circa 12 - 15 framed photographs.
Manuscript drafts, transcripts, field notes, correspondence, speeches, publications and research materials, chiefly related to the research and writings of P. Marcel Kurpershoek, in particular his work on oral poetry traditions of Bedouin tribes of central Saudi Arabia. Also includes materials related to other writings by Kurpershoek, including manuscript drafts and research materials for his doctoral dissertation on the Egyptian writer, Yusuf Idris.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for use in the Archives and Special Collections Reading Room, New York University Abu Dhabi Library.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by P. Marcel Kurpershoek, 2018, with accretions in 2020 and 2021.
Arrangement
The Marcel Kurpershoek collection is arranged in seven series: I. Publications, II. Correspondence, speeches and miscellaneous writings, III. Research notes and background materials, IV. Dissertation and other academic materials, V. Printed materials, VI. Photographs and other miscellanea, VII. Sound recordings, VIII. Film footage. The series are arranged largely in alphabetical order by folder title, with some sub-series added in the "Publications" series for materials related to individual published works.
Biographical statement
Paul Marcel Kurpershoek was born in The Hague, the Netherlands, in 1949. After completing his secondary schooling (Gymnasium) in 1967, he attended the University of Leiden for his undergraduate degree, studying Arabic literature, completing his studies there in 1970, following which he spent a year of further study in Cairo, and obtained his MA at the University of Leiden in 1973. In 1975, he joined the diplomatic service of the Foreign Ministry of the Netherlands, and during the next several decades, served in postings in Egypt, Syria, Saudi Arabia, among other locations, including an eight-year period of service at the Ministry in The Hague, where he was Director of Middle East and North African Affairs. He later served as the Netherlands Ambassador to Pakistan, Afghanistan, Turkey, and Poland, and as a Dutch special representative for Syria, based in Istanbul. He retired from the Foreign Ministry in 2014.
During his diplomatic career, he also pursued a scholarly one, completing a doctorate in Arabic literature from the University of Leiden in 1980, with a dissertation about the Egyptian short story writer Yūsuf Idrīs, subsequently published as "The short stories of Yūsuf Idrīs: a modern Egyptian author" (Leiden: Brill, 1981). During his posting in Riyadh in the late 1980s, his interest in the oral poetic traditions of Bedouin tribes of central Saudi Arabia led him to take a sabbatical year between postings in 1989 to conduct field work in Nejd and Wadi Dawasir, recording and transcribing such poetry, also known as Nabati poetry. The resulting work led to the publication of five scholarly volumes of such poetry, with transcriptions, translations, and scholarly analyses, titled "Oral Poetry and Narratives of Central Arabia" (Leiden: Brill, 1994-2005).
He also authored several several titles about his field work in Arabia for a popular audience, including "Diep in Arabië"(Amsterdam: Meulenhoff, 1992), "De laatste Bedoeïen"(Amsterdam: Meulenhoff, 1995), and an English translation and adaptation of those two titles, "Arabia of the Bedouins" (London: Saqi Books, 2001), as well an Arabic translation of the latter title, "al-Badawī al-akhīr: al-qabāʼil al-badawīyah fī al-ṣaḥrāʼ al-ʻArabīyah" (London / Beirut: Saqi Books, 2002), among other books, essays, and journal articles. His interest in the wider Middle East also led him to publish a book about the history of various claims to Jerusalem, "Onzalig Jeruzalem" (Amsterdam: Meulenhoff, 1996).
During the latter years of his diplomatic service, and following his retirement, Kurpershoek continued his scholarly work on Arabic literature and Nabati poetry. He was appointed Professor of Arabic Literature and Politics at the University of Leiden in 1996, serving in that post until 2001, and in 2015 he joined New York University Abu Dhabi as a Senior Research Fellow in the Humanities Research Fellowship Program. In this latter program, he has published further works through the university's Library of Arabic Literature series, including "Arabian Satire: Poetry from 18th century Najd," "Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love," and "Love, Death, Fame: Poetry and Lore from the Emirati Oral Tradition" (New York: NYU Press, 2017, 2018, and 2022). In addition, his fieldwork in Saudi Arabia was profiled in a television documentary on the al Arabiya network in 2017 and 2018 titled "The Last Traveller"(al-Raḥḥālat al-akhīr)and "Monuments of Poetry" (Qāmāt al-qaṣīd).
Content Description
The collection consists of manuscript drafts, transcripts, field notes, correspondence, speeches, publications and research materials, chiefly related to the research and writings of P. Marcel Kurpershoek, in particular his work on oral poetry traditions of Bedouin tribes of central Saudi Arabia. Also includes materials related to other writings by Kurpershoek, including manuscript drafts and research materials for his doctoral dissertation on the Egyptian writer, Yusuf Idris.
The collection is divided into seven series. The "Publications" series contains manuscript and typescript drafts, notes, and other materials used or created by Kurpershoek in the writing and editing of several of his books, including the "Oral Poetry and Narratives of Central Arabia," his chief scholarly work on Nabati poetry. The materials related to that often demonstrate his process of recording, transcribing, and translating poetry that Bedouins recited to him during his field work in Saudi Arabia, and often include notebooks in which he first transcribed these poems from audio recordings he had made, and then subsequent drafts in Arabic, with edits and corrections provided by the poets or those close to them, or from other scholars he worked with, primarily Saad Sowayan, the foremost Saudi scholar of Nabati poetry. Materials related to the writing and research of Kurpershoek's later works, including the titles published as part of the NYU Abu Dhabi's Library of Arabic Literature, were added in 2021.
The "Correspondence, speeches and other writings" groups together a smaller amount of material, ranging from speeches or brief articles compiled by Kurpershoek about Nabati poetry and his field work in Saudi Arabia, to copies of correspondence he sent to his wife, Betsy Udink, during his trips to Nejd or elsewhere in Saudi Arabia, in which he describes his experiences and field work. Additional correspondence with other scholars and editors is included in this series as well.
The "Research notes and background materials" contains chiefly notes compiled by Kurpershoek from secondary sources, but also includes notebooks from his fieldwork and research trips, as well as scholarly papers and offprints, most notably from scholars of Nabati poetry and related poetic traditions, as well as papers presented at a conference in Riyadh on traditional oral poetry in 1988. The "Printed materials" series contain copies of books or other difficult to obtain published materials related to Nabati poetry, and used by Kurpershoek in his research.
The series "Dissertation and other academic materials" relates primarily to Kurpershoek's research and writing of his dissertation on the Egyptian writer Yūsuf Idrīs, including transcripts of interviews Kurpershoek conducted with Idrīs, news clippings from the Egyptian press about Idrīs, drafts of Kurpershoek's dissertation text, and a Dutch translation by Kurpershoek of one of Idrīs's short stories, "al- Ḥarām." Also included are notes retained by Kurpershoek during an earlier study visit to Cairo in 1970, and materials related to the granting of his doctorate at the University of Leiden in 1980.
The "Photographs" series, consists chiefly color slides and prints taken in Saudi Arabia (and to a lesser extent, Oman), during multiple research trips from the late 1980s to the late 1990s. Many of the slides are identified in inventories created by Kurpershoek, with many of the images corresponding to events described in the book "Arabia of the Bedouins," or related to poets whose works were highlighted in his other publications. This series also includes a few images enlarged as poster-sized reproductions.
The "Sound Recordings" series consists primarily of field recordings made by Kurpershoek, beginning in the late 1980s, of recitations of Nabati poetry in various locations in Saudi Arabia. Also included are recordings of radio broadcasts of interviews with Kurpershoek, on stations in the Netherlands, usually relating to books that Kurpershoek had recently published, or about his views on current events in the Middle East.
The series "Film Footage" contains raw footage created by staff with Middle East News and the Al Arabiya television network, for use in a documentary film about Kurpershoek titled "The Last Traveler" in 2017. The film is still in process at the time of the creation of this finding aid, but shows Kurpershoek visiting, interviewing, and holding discussions with a number of Saudi Bedouin poets, among other materials utilized in the documentary, and is under license to Middle East News. Additional video content includes recordings of television programs featuring Kurpershoek, usually in the Netherlands.
Dialect poetry, Arabic -- Saudi Arabia -- Najd; Arabic poetry -- Saudi Arabia; Najd (Saudi Arabia); Dawāsir Wadi (Saudi Arabia); Idrīs, Yūsuf -- Criticism and interpretation
- Publications, circa 1988-2020
  - Oral Poetry and Narratives from Central Arabia: Volume 1: The Poetry of ad-Dindan
    - Glossary, manuscript (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Glossary, typescript (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript draft (preface and introduction) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Notes on transcribed texts of poetry (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Transcriptions of poetry (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Typescript text of volume, with edits (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Oral Poetry and Narratives from Central Arabia: Volume 2: The Story of a Desert Knight
    - Glossary—manuscript (1) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Glossary—manuscript (2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Glossary—typescript, with edits by Saad Sowayan (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript draft of text, "Khaled I" (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript draft of text, "Khaled II" (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Metrical studies (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Place names (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Poetry, transcripts of (Latin script) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Poetry, transcripts of (Arabic script), initial transcripts in "Record Book" (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Poetry, transcripts of, (Arabic script), with annotations and edits made in field, from poets and transmitters. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Text, manuscript draft, "Language and Prosody" (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Text, manuscript draft, "Variant Readings of Poems" (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Text, typescript draft, with edits by Saad Sowayan (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Oral Poetry and Narratives from Central Arabia: Volume 3:. Bedouin Poets of the Dawasir Tribe
    - Notes and questions (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Poetry: Bkheitan: photocopy of transcribed poems written down by Bkheitan (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Poetry: Bkheitan: transcripts with edits (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Poetry: ad-Dindan: transcripts (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Poetry: Ibn Batla: translations (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Poetry: Ibn Batla: transcripts (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Poetry: transcripts, general (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Oral Poetry and Narratives from Central Arabia: Volume 4:. A Saudi Tribal History, 1995-2002, and undated
    - Correspondence: Bearman, Peri, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Editorial, general, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Gelder, Geert van, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Sowayan, Saad, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Notes: general (1) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Notes: general (2) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Notes: historical and background (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Notes: "Muṣliḥah," or "peace poem" (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Notes: topical (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Poetry: transcripts, fragments (manuscript) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Poetry: transcripts, general, arranged by location on tape recordings (1) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Poetry: transcripts, general, arranged by location on tape recordings (2) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Poetry: transcripts, Arabic script ("Record Book") (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): general (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): Bkhitan (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): Nādir al-Nāhish (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): Saied ibn Murdi (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): Mit'ib (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): Farruj (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): Saqr (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): Fahed ibn Reyn (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): Dindan (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Poetry: transcripts (from red binder, Arabic script): Ibn Nuwayyir (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Poetry: transcripts: al-Nāhish and Ibn Ḥuṣn (Latin script) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Poetry: transcripts: al-Nāhish: typescript (Arabic script) with edits and annotations by Mājid al-Nāhish, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Poetry: Bkheitan: transcripts, manuscript (Latin script), February 1999 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Travel plans for field work, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Typescript text, with edits (1) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Typescript text, with edits (2) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Oral Poetry and Narratives from Central Arabia: unidentified materials and miscellaneous
    - Poetry transcripts: manuscript (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Poetry transcripts: typescript (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Reviews and articles the series (Arabic), undated, circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Other writings: Diep in Arabië, De laatste Bedoeïen, Onzalige Jerusalem
    - Diep in Arabië: outline (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Diep in Arabië: manuscript draft (1) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Diep in Arabië: manuscript draft (2) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Diep in Arabië: manuscript draft (3) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Diep in Arabië: manuscript draft (4) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Diep in Arabië: manuscript draft (5) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Diep in Arabië: poetry: poem about coffee, Dubais al-ʿUlawī (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Diep in Arabië: poetry: Gana (Qana) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Diep in Arabië: promotion (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Diep in Arabië: typescript draft (1) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Diep in Arabië: typescript draft (2) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Diep in Arabië: typescript draft (3) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Diep in Arabië: typescript draft: sent to mother for review (1) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Diep in Arabië: typescript draft: sent to mother for review (2) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - De laatste Bedoeïen: manuscript draft (1) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - De laatste Bedoeïen: manuscript draft (2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: background materials (1) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: background materials (2) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: manuscript draft (1) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: manuscript draft (2) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: manuscript draft (3) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: manuscript draft (4) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: manuscript draft (5) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: manuscript draft, fragments (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: notes (1) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: notes (2) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Onzalige Jerusalem: photographs, negatives (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Arabia of the Bedouins: review, by Margaret Obank, in "Banipal," No. 14, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Other writings: Library of Arabic Literature (NYU Abu Dhabi)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (Ibn Sbayyil): Arabic typescript texts, with edits in red (1) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): Arabic typescript texts, with edits in red (2) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): edits and corrections, Clive Holes (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): edits and corrections, Saad Sowayyan (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): notes (1) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): notes (2) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): notes and bibliography (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Poetry: Ibn Sbayyil: Library of Arabic Literature publication project, "Arabian Romantic". Poems recorded in KSA from Adbullah Nafish and transcribed by PMK (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): sources, copied text with handwritten annotations (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): sources, copied text with annotations (2) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): source texts, photocopied from notebook (1) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): source texts, photocopied from notebook (2) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): source texts, photocopied from notebook (3) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): source texts, photocopied from notebook (4) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): translated texts of poems, with edits in red and blue, by S. Sowayyan (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): transliterated texts of poems, with edits in red (Kurpershoek) and blue (Sowayyan) (2) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): transliterated texts of poems, with edits in red (Kurpershoek) and blue (Sowayyan) (3) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): Background articles and miscellaneous, 1994, and undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): Photocopies of texts of proverbs, cited by Ibn Sbayyil in poetry (1) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Arabian Romantic: Poems on Bedouin Life and Love (ʿAbdallāh ibn Sbayyil): Photocopies of texts of proverbs, cited by Ibn Sbayyil in poetry (2) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Arabian Satire: Poetry from 18th century Najd (Ḥmēdān al-Shwēʿir): notes, manuscript (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Arabian Satire: Poetry from 18th century Najd (Ḥmēdān al-Shwēʿir): sources, photocopied text from published works, with annotations (1) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Arabian Satire: Poetry from 18th century Najd (Ḥmēdān al-Shwēʿir): sources, photocopied text from manuscript, notebook (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Arabian Satire: Poetry from 18th century Najd (Ḥmēdān al-Shwēʿir): sources, bound photocopy of manuscript notebook, titled "Diwān Ḥmēdān al-Shwēʿir" (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Arabian Satire: Poetry from 18th century Najd (Ḥmēdān al-Shwēʿir): sources, photocopy from Huber manuscript (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Arabian Satire: Poetry from 18th century Najd (Ḥmēdān al-Shwēʿir): sources, photocopied pages from manuscript text (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Arabian Satire: Poetry from 18th century Najd (Ḥmēdān al-Shwēʿir): transcribed text, with edits in red (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Arabian Satire: Poetry from 18th century Najd (Ḥmēdān al-Shwēʿir): transliterated text, with edits in red (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials (copied): Arabic stories (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 1 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 2 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 3 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 4 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 5 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 6 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 7 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 8 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 9 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 10 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 11 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 12 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 13 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 14 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 15 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Notes and source materials, Poem 16 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Place names (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Source materials, photocopied: Dīwān al-shā'ir al-Sha'bī (ibn Dhahir) (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Source materials, various (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Love, Death and Fame: Poetry and lore from the Emirati oral tradition (al-Māyidī ibn Ẓāhir): Source materials, photocopied: proverbs (Box 9, Folder 13)